MUHAMMAD ANAS

Software Engineering Student & Graphic Designer

+92 312 2296914 anasarif216@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ianasarif

ABOUT ME

A dedicated Software engineering Student with a variety of problem-solving skills. I am Currently passionate about Javascript and its frameworks. I believe in self Learning and avail opportunities at any stage of life.

Apart from Software Engineering, I do graphic designing as well. With a good amount of experience with tools like Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, and Adobe Xd I have created many designs and I love implementing fresh ideas and work in collaborative projects.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: React js, Node js, Express, Javascript (with ES6 features), Python, SQL, No

SQL(MongoDB), HTML, CSS and Git

Designing Skills: Illustration, Brand Identity Designing, Logos, UI/UX designing, Banners, Infographics

Amazon Listing and A+ content, and Typography

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

October, 2020 - Present

- Freelancing
- Developed responsive websites with HTML/CSS
- Developed frontend with react [redux and hooks implementation]
- Builded small-scale projects with Python.

Graphic Designer

December, 2019 - January, 2021

- Rawts, Karachi
- Designed social media marketing posts, banners, posters, ads, etc.
- Responsible for creating illustrations, logos, and other designs.
- Created and designed UI

EDUCATION

BS Software Engineering, Karachi

January 2020 - Present

University of Karachi
 [6th semester currently]

Intermediate, Karachi

September 2017 - April 2019

- Govt. Delhi College

Matriculation, Karachi

Till April 2017

- The Metropolitan Academy

LINKS

linkedin.com/in/ianasarif behance.net/iAnas19 github.com/iAnas19

TOOLS

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Flgma, VS Code, Adobe Xd, Pycharm

PROJECTS

Devconnector

Employment-oriented social network for developers, built on the MERN stack with authentication with JWT.

Code at: https://github.com/iAnas19/Dev-Connector

GoalSetter

MERN web application to write and save goals. Deployed at: http://goalsetterpk.herokuapp.com/

StoryBooks

Story publishing webapp made from NODE is and Mongodb alongwith google auth. Code at: https://github.com/iAnas19/StoryBooks

BankEase

React.js Website for Online Banking.

Deployed at: https://ianas19.github.io/BankEase/

CERTIFICATION AND LICENSES

Python Data science completion certificate from DataCamp

Completed on March 2020

SQL completion by Testdome

Completed on August 2022